(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T00:45:46.428633",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
澄み渡る青は いつもはじまりを強く照らすから
The crystal-clear blue always shines so brightly on new beginnings
本当は震えている手足が隠せないよ
So much so, I can't hide these hands and feet, truly trembling
物語の先はどう？ 君なら何色で描く？
What lies ahead in our story? What colors would you use to paint it?
咽び泣いた日のこと やりきれなかった日のことを
Those days I sobbed uncontrollably, those days I just couldn't stop...
ツバメみたいに速く飛べたらいいのに
If only I could fly as swiftly as a swallow...
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから
I need nothing more, for I won't let this be forgotten
どこまでも遠くへと このまま手をつないで take a journey
So let's journey far, far away, holding hands just like this, take a journey
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を超えて
As if swimming through tears, let's cross the pale darkness
いびつな翼で渡ろうよ 無限の夏の空へ
With these misshapen wings, let's fly on, to the infinite summer sky
失くした鍵は見つかった？ 燃えるゴミの日に出しちゃった？
Did you find what you had lost? Or did you toss it out on trash day?
いつの間にか煤けた君のスペシャルな夢の船
Before you knew it, your special ship of dreams had gathered dust and soot
子供みたいに青く願えたらいいのに
If only I could wish for things with the pure, boundless blue of a child...
気付けば檻の中で
But when I came to, I found myself within a cage
胸の隅で疼いて泣くのはきっと大事なものだから
That ache, that cry from my heart—it must be because it's precious
間違えても彷徨っても離さないでいようね
Even if I blunder, even if I wander lost, let's hold on and never let it go
空の果て 群青のその先を見つめて 飛びたいのこの命賭けて
Gazing beyond the sky's horizon, beyond that deep blue... I want to fly, staking my life on it
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから
I need nothing more, for I won't let this be forgotten
どこまでも遠くへと ありのまま紡いで take a journey
So let's journey far, far away, weaving our story just as we are, take a journey
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を超えて
As if swimming through tears, let's cross the pale darkness
いびつな翼でいいよ 行こう 無限の夏の空へ いつも君が明るく放って支えてくれるね
Misshapen wings are fine, let's go! To the infinite summer sky... You always brightly shine and support me
ずっと刻まれて光るよ
Etched forever, shining on
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を超えて いびつな翼で渡ろうよ 無限の夏の空へ
As if swimming through tears, let's cross the pale darkness with these misshapen wings to the infinite summer sky
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから どこまでも遠くへと このまま手をつないで take a journey
I need nothing more, for I won't let this be forgotten, so let's journey far, far away, holding hands just like this
最近の始まりちょっと 世界を飛ばしちゃって
Let's skip the world a bit with this recent start,
君の心のときめきを もっと！
and show your heart's excitement even more!
聴こえてる？ 聞かせてよ ナツコイ！
Can you hear it? Let me hear it: Summer Love!
順風満帆の風 聴こえてきてんの
Can you hear the favorable wind blowing?
無茶して今夜も直滑降 すれすれ平行線
Recklessly schussing tonight too, skimming parallel lines,
世界線揺らす
shaking the world line!
もう一回！ もっと求めたい！
Once more! I want more!
飛んで！ この指に止まれ
Fly! Perch on this finger,
繋いだ手と 状態
joined hands and state of being,
笑った数じゃ足りない
the number of laughs isn't enough!
永遠ノーライク もう一回！
Forever no-like, once more!
もう待てない！ 今すぐ会って
I can't wait anymore! Meet me right now,
センター！ えんだたったっがたった！
center! En-da-tat-ta-ga-tat-ta!
最近の始まりちょっと 世界を飛ばしちゃって
Let's skip the world a bit with this recent start,
キミの音色が響いてるんだ
and your tone is echoing through.
一期一会のジャンプ ブレを伸ばしちゃって
Stretching the blur of a once-in-a-lifetime jump,
一度でいいから 心躍らせたよ
just once, let your heart dance!
今日が秒で
Today passes in a second,
その声を聴かせてよ
let me hear your voice!
夢の芯まで 手を伸ばしてよ
Reach out to the very core of your dreams,
コンプレックスを飛ばして アナログに描いて
skip past complexes and draw it analogly,
ドキドキのアイラヴ
a pounding "I love you,"
サイコーは 一秒止められないこの状態
the best state that can't be stopped for even a second!
もう一回！ もう待てない！
Once more! I can't wait anymore!
何度知らぬ視線が のぞき町に飛び込んで
Unfamiliar gazes dive into the bustling town,
もっと遠くへ行きたくなよって
wanting to go even further,
何度止められない この状態
this state that still can't be stopped,
教えてあげるんだ
I'll teach you!
えんだたったっがたった！ 一期一会のジャンプ 世界線を憎みちゃって
En-da-tat-ta-ga-tat-ta! A once-in-a-lifetime jump, hating the world line,
キミの熱気を感じるんだ
feeling your passion.
ここが正気だっちゃって 帰りたくない
Going crazy here, I don't want to go home,
一期一会の手を伸ばしてよ
reach out your hand for a once-in-a-lifetime moment,
キミに愛を届けてよ セツナを越え続けて
delivering love to you, crossing through fleeting moments,
もっともっと溢れて 一途でだからやり切ってよ
overflowing more and more, single-mindedly pushing through,
今日が秒で 鳴らしてよ
today passing in seconds, let it ring out!
その声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear your voice!
夢の芯まで 手を伸ばしてよ
Reach out to the very core of your dreams,
コンプレックスを飛ばして アナログに描いて
skip past complexes and draw it analogly,
ドキドキのアイラヴ
a pounding "I love you,"
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting for you!
鳴らしてよ 鳴らしてよ
Ring it out, ring it out!
ありがたみのキャンバスにあなた
On a canvas of gratitude, you
まだ緑を散り
are still scattering green...
一歩目を踏み出して ここから
Take your first step from here,
始まったストーリー 夢で見た景色は
the story that began, the scenery I saw in a dream...
憧れを叶えて
fulfilling my longing,
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting for you!
あの日の空に 君を見つけた通り
just like finding you in that day's sky,
戻るの
returning...
いつも待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
Always waiting, waiting, waiting for you!
夢の方へ目掛けて きっとどうか届いて
Aiming towards the dream, surely, please let it reach you!
えがわ広げて ただたたずむの
Spreading out the smile, just standing still,
ネスのあてる 夢みたいな色で
with colors like a dream...
まだまだ追いかけて チャレンジは止まらない
Still chasing, the challenge never stops!
ネットで音をつなげて
Connecting sounds over the net,
connecting sounds over the net,
私待ってるよ 待ってるよ 待ってるよ
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting for you!
今もずっとここで 犬の日が君を見つけて
Even now right here, finding you...
くれるように ねえ待ってるよ
I hope it happens, hey, I'm waiting!
真夜中だ 目を覚ませ
Wake up at midnight, wake up your eyes
波長が合うヤツ集まれ
Gather around, those whose wavelengths match
今夜楽しむため来たゲリラ
I came tonight to have fun, guerrilla!
声枯れるまで騒ごうぜ
Let's make noise until our voices are gone!
遊ぼうぜ この指止まれ
Let's play, stop on this finger!
感じるまま今夜もトバせ
Fly freely tonight as you feel!
男は紳士に 女の子に
Men, be gentlemen to the girls!
根拠ない自信で飛び込め
Dive in with groundless confidence!
何言われようがしたたかに
No matter what they say, stay cool!
明日のことは関係ない
The future doesn't matter!
ザワつかせるメンタルは狂気
The mental that shakes you is madness!
オレらの新天地
Our new frontier!
さあ燃え尽きろ どこまでも
Come on, burn out to the ends of the earth!
君をcrazyにさせたい
I want to make you crazy!
b.i.g yea we bang like this みんな一緒に
B.I.G yeah we bang like this, everyone together!
一撃でゾッコン
Love at first sight!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
みんな動くな まだ動くな
Everyone, don't move! Don't move yet!
今夜は最後まで対決だ
Tonight is a showdown until the very end!
今夜は最後まで
Tonight, until the end...
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
今夜は付き合ってもらうぜ
I'll have you join me tonight!
真っ赤に空が染まる時
When the sky turns deep red...
二人だけ踊る ここはvalhalla
The two of us dance, this is Valhalla!
遠く彼方まで響け
Resonate to the distant horizon!
we go hard 注意しろ! どこでも瞬時移動
We go hard, watch out! Teleportation anywhere!
祈れgod 自問自答してられない状況
Pray god, a situation where you can't even self-question!
月明かりで吠えるメロディー 暗闇で集まり
Melody howling by moonlight, gathering in the darkness...
飛び散らかす四方八方 五方 whoo
Scattering in all directions, whoo!
さあ燃え尽きろ どこまでも
Come on, burn out to the ends of the earth!
君をcrazyにさせたい
I want to make you crazy!
b.i.g yea we bang like this みんな一緒に
B.I.G yeah we bang like this, everyone together!
一撃でゾッコン
Love at first sight!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
みんな動くな まだ動くな
Everyone, don't move! Don't move yet!
今夜は最後まで対決だ
Tonight is a showdown until the very end!
今夜は最後まで
Tonight, until the end...
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
ready or not
yea we don't give a what
Yeah, we don't give a what!
ready or not
yea we don't give a what
Yeah, we don't give a what!
let's go メンズはアゲろ
Let's go, men raise it up!
ladiesはget low
Ladies, get low!
さあ今 bang bang bang
Now, come on, Bang Bang Bang!
let the bass drum go
メンズはアゲろ
Men raise it up!
ladiesはget low
Ladies, get low!
さあ今 bang bang bang
Now, come on, Bang Bang Bang!
let the bass drum go
真夜中だ 目を覚ませ
Wake up at midnight, wake up your eyes!
波長が合うヤツ集まれ
Gather around, those whose wavelengths match!
今夜楽しむため来たゲリラ
I came tonight to have fun, guerrilla!
声枯れるまで騒ごうぜ
Let's make noise until our voices are gone!
遊ぼうぜ この指止まれ
Let's play, stop on this finger!
感じるまま今夜もトバせ
Fly freely tonight as you feel!
男は紳士に 女の子に
Men, be gentlemen to the girls!
根拠ない自信で飛び込め
Dive in with groundless confidence!
何言われようがしたたかに
No matter what they say, stay cool!
明日のことは関係ない
The future doesn't matter!
ザワつかせるメンタルは狂気
The mental that shakes you is madness!
オレらの新天地
Our new frontier!
さあ燃え尽きろ どこまでも
Come on, burn out to the ends of the earth!
君をcrazyにさせたい
I want to make you crazy!
b.i.g yea we bang like this みんな一緒に
B.I.G yeah we bang like this, everyone together!
一撃でゾッコン
Love at first sight!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
みんな動くな まだ動くな
Everyone, don't move! Don't move yet!
今夜は最後まで対決だ
Tonight is a showdown until the very end!
今夜は最後まで
Tonight, until the end...
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
今夜は付き合ってもらうぜ
I'll have you join me tonight!
真っ赤に空が染まる時
When the sky turns deep red...
二人だけ踊る ここはvalhalla
The two of us dance, this is Valhalla!
遠く彼方まで響け
Resonate to the distant horizon!
we go hard 注意しろ! どこでも瞬時移動
We go hard, watch out! Teleportation anywhere!
祈れgod 自問自答してられない状況
Pray god, a situation where you can't even self-question!
月明かりで吠えるメロディー 暗闇で集まり
Melody howling by moonlight, gathering in the darkness...
飛び散らかす四方八方 五方 whoo
Scattering in all directions, whoo!
さあ燃え尽きろ どこまでも
Come on, burn out to the ends of the earth!
君をcrazyにさせたい
I want to make you crazy!
b.i.g yea we bang like this みんな一緒に
B.I.G yeah we bang like this, everyone together!
一撃でゾッコン
Love at first sight!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
bang! bang! bang!
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
みんな動くな まだ動くな
Everyone, don't move! Don't move yet!
今夜は最後まで対決だ
Tonight is a showdown until the very end!
今夜は最後まで
Tonight, until the end...
パンヤ パンヤ パンヤ
Pang-ya, pang-ya, pang-ya!
ready or not
yea we don't give a what
Yeah, we don't give a what!
ready or not
yea we don't give a what
Yeah, we don't give a what!
みんなー 見えてるー? 聞こえてるー?
Everyone... can you see me? Can you hear me?
はい、というわけで
So, as it turns out,
今日も2日目、スターパ2025ですよー！
today is day two of Starpa 2025!
み、今返っちゃった。聞いてる、聞こえてる。
Wait, my voice is already echoing back at me... I can hear it!
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you guys so much!
2日目も始めるよー！はははは。
Day two is starting off right now, haha!
昨日もやりましたが、今日もね、あの、掛け声みんなでやっていきましょうね！
We did it yesterday too, but today let's all do the call-and-response together, okay?
やー、というわけで、
So, yeah!
はー、1年半ぶりなんですよ。ま、昨日ぶりだから
It's been a year and a half... Well, since it was yesterday,
ま、1日ぶりですね。はははは。
it's really just been a day, huh? Haha!
ま、今日も2日目だよって人ー！
So, who's here for day two?
もう、今日が初めてだよって人ー！
And who's here for the very first time today?
そもそもライブ自体初めてですよって人ー！
And who's experiencing a live concert for the very first time ever?
おー！じゃあライブデビューですね！ありがとうございます！
Oh! Welcome to your first live! Thank you so much!
では、全員に声出してもらいたいな！とりあえず、全員！
Now, I want everyone to make some noise! Let's start with—everybody!
声出せるかな？出せなかったら、まあ手で振るだけでもいいよね！女の子ー！
Can you guys make some noise? If you can't, just waving your hands is fine too! All the girls!
次、学生席！
Next up, all the students!
海外の皆さんー！
And everyone joining us from overseas!
正面とー！そして、えー、左の皆さんー！
Everyone in the center seats! And everyone on the left!
右の皆さんー！全員ー！
And the right! Everyone!
やー、最高じゃないですか！みんな声出る準備できてるって感じ？
Yes, isn't this amazing? Everyone's voice is ready to go, right?
みんなね、見えてる見えてる！前のほう、後ろの方、前のほう、後ろの方、どこ見てんだろね！はははは。
Everyone's waving: front, back, front, back... Where are you even looking?! Haha!
はい、とー。あ、ありがと、ありがと、ありがと！うーん。
Yes, thank you, thank you, thank you!
や、みんなのね、応援も今日なんかざりてぃー率高いね！めちゃくちゃ青い。なんか、セカ—
Everyone's cheering is so bright today! It's so overwhelmingly blue—
世界が青い！あ、ざりてぃーじゃないのか？もしかしてあれかな？
Wait, is it "zarity"? Or maybe...
今回のライブのTシャツの人もいる？
is anyone wearing this live's T-shirt?
あ、やっぱそうだよね！Tシャツも青だもんね！
Ah, right! The T-shirts are blue too, aren't they?
すごくありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
もーね、みんなが外で写真撮って「来た！」、今から待ちきれないってやってるの、すっごい見てましたから、ありがとうございます！
I've been watching everyone outside taking photos and going, "I'm here!" and not being able to wait—thank you so much for watching!
とね、こうやって喋ってるんですが、YouTubeをご覧の皆さん……えー！えー！
And so, while I'm chatting away here, to everyone watching on YouTube...
えー！まだ始まったばかりなんだけど、あの、本当に3曲しかやってないからまだ来たばかりかもしれない。や、もの足りないなーって思う人、
Well, since it just started, maybe we're only playing three songs, so it might end really soon!
ぜひね、なんかど、ここ、ここ、どこ、どこ、どっかに概要欄があるので、そこから、ま、3日券とか買って続きを見てもらえると、私、あ、叫んだ！
if you want more, please check the description box below—you can keep watching for the whole three days! I'm shouting! Haha!
とっても嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be so happy!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
というわけで、さっそくね、おしゃべりばっかしてたらただの雑談枠になっちゃうのでね！はははは。
So anyway, if I just keep chatting, this is just going to turn into a talk show, right? Haha!
次の曲目にもいってく、いこうと思うんですが、まあね、昨日歌えなくて待ってた曲あるんじゃない？
I want to move on to the next song, but... well, we didn't sing it yesterday, so there are some new songs, right?
次の曲は、はーい！新アルバムから「ダンサブルナ」、ダンス、ダンス、ダンスの曲を歌ってみようと思います！
The next song is from her new album—let's sing "Dansaburuna", a dance, dance, dance song!
(フッフー！) (フーワッフーワッ！)
(Fufu!) (Fuwafuwafuwa!)
我々の宇宙のはじまりは (パパヤ)
Our universe's beginning (Pa-pa-ya)
触れた瞬間 アララララ (パパヤ)
The moment we touched, arararara (Pa-pa-ya)
はぁ〜、これは困った！
Whoops, this is a pickle!
二度ともとにもどらない 大！爆！発！
No turning back now—big explosion!
そして星が生まれまして (パパヤ)
And then stars were born (Pa-pa-ya)
明け方の 一番星は (パパヤ)
The morning star is (Pa-pa-ya)
このままハート打ち上げ どこまでもたかい宇宙まで
Launch that heart straight up, soaring to the distant universe!
「めちゃ飛び出しちゃっ！」
"We flew way too high!"
さあスター・スター・スタート きったこのラブは
Now, star-star-start, this love we found
冒頭無料配信はこちらで終了です。★ライブチケット購入はコチラ SPWN/
This free preview stream ends here. ★Click here to purchase live tickets: SPWN/